A Finding Aid to the Galerie Chalette Records, 1916-1999, bulk 1939-1994, in the Archives of American Art AAA.galechal
Archives of American Art
Galerie Chalette records
bulk 1939-1994
1916-1999
AAA.galechal
Archives of American Art
23.4 Linear feet
The records of the New York Galerie Chalette measure 23.4 linear feet and date from 1916-1999, with the bulk of the material dating from 1939-1994. The collection documents this contemporary art gallery's operations from its founding in 1954 through Madeleine Lejwa's later years as an independent dealer. Included are correspondence, artists' files, financial and legal records, printed materials, clippings, exhibition catalogs, audio and video recordings, and motion picture film; about half of the collection consists of photographs. Arthur Lejwa's profession as a biochemist prior to becoming a gallery owner is also documented in this collection. The collection also contains personal records of the Lejwas, including correspondence, legal papers, photographs, photo albums, and printed material.
Galerie Chalette
Provenance
The records were donated by Robert Warshaw, executor of the Madeleine Chalette Lejwa estate in two accessions in 1997 and 2005.
Separated Material
Papers related to Leon Chalette's imprisonment in Sachsenhausen concentration camp were transferred to the Leo Baeck Institute, New York, N.Y. in 2010.
Related Material
Addition papers related to Leon Chalette and Madeleine Chalette are located at Leo Baeck Institute, New York, N.Y.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment. Use of archival audiovisual recordings with no duplicate access copy requires advance notice.
Historical Note
Art dealers and collectors Madeleine Chalette (1915-1996) and Arthur Lejwa (1895-1972) opened the Galerie Chalette in New York on 45 West 57th Street in February, 1954. The gallery originally specialized in contemporary French graphics and later shifted its focus to contemporary twentieth century European and American art, particularly the work of Jean Arp. Over the years, Galerie Chalette relocated twice. In 1957, the gallery moved to 1100 Madison Avenue and then to 9 East 88th Street in 1964.
Madeleine Chalette was born in 1915 in Paris and grew up in Poland. In 1940, after Madeleine's efforts to secure the release of her father, Leon Chalette, from Sachsenhausen concentration camp near Berlin were successful, father and daughter traveled by boat to Shanghai. They stayed in Shanghai throughout World War II, arriving in the United States in 1946. Arthur Lejwa, a Polish-born biochemist, immigrated to the United States in 1939 and taught at Long Island University. In 1947, Madeleine and Arthur Lejwa were married in Cincinnati, Ohio where Arthur was the Director of the Robert Gould Institute for Nutritional Research.
The gallery was very active in the 1950s and 1960s, as evidenced by the numerous exhibitions. Many of the exhibitions in the 1950s were thematic. Exhibitions in the 1960s were mostly organized around the work of a particular artist, such as Wojciech Fangor and Leon Polk Smith. In 1972, the Metropolitan Museum of Art showcased Jean Arp's work from the Lejwa's collection and a few works lent by Arp's widow, Marguerite Arp. The exhibition was expanded and traveled as "Arp 1877-1966," first exhibited at the Solomon R. Guggenheim Museum and then shown in seven museums in the United States and six in Australia.
In the early 1970s, the Lejwas began supporting institutions in Jerusalem, including donating a 17th century Polish menorah to The Israel Museum and five sculptures to be displayed in public spaces: "The Threshold of Jerusalem" by Jean Arp, "The Loop" by Robert Engman, George Rickey's "Two Lines Oblique," "The Skedion Ekton" by Stephanie Scuris, and "Four Cubes Cut in Identical Halves" by Max Bill.
Following Arthur's death on October 27, 1972, Madeleine continued as an independent dealer and consultant and renamed the business Chalette International. In the 1980s, Madeleine Lejwa continued her philanthropic endeavors in Jerusalem, donating to a scholarship fund for Arab students. She was also a strong supporter of New York University's archeological site Aphrodisias, in southwestern Turkey. In the 1970s and 1980s, Lejwa traveled widely including Israel, Jordan, Egypt, Italy, Turkey, Japan, and China. Madeleine passed away at age 81 on June 9, 1996.
Scope and Content Note
The records of the New York Galerie Chalette measure 23.4 linear feet and date from 1916-1999, with the bulk of the material dating from 1939-1994. The collection documents this contemporary art gallery's operations from its founding in 1954 through Madeleine Lejwa's later years as an independent dealer. Included are correspondence, artists' files, financial and legal records, printed materials, clippings, exhibition catalogs, audio and video recordings, and motion picture film; about half of the collection consists of photographs. Arthur Lejwa's profession as a biochemist prior to becoming a gallery owner is also documented in this collection. The collection also contains personal records of the Lejwas, including correspondence, legal papers, photographs, photo albums, and printed material.
Among the artists represented in the artists' files are Jean Arp, Max Bill, Burgoyne Diller, Wojciech Fangor, Sue Fuller, Julio Gonzalez, Roberta Gonzalez, Lazlo Moholy-Nagy, William Reimann, George Rickey, Leon Polk Smith, Victor Varsarely, Max Weber, and various Dada artists. Many artists are represented in the large collection of photographs as is the Lejwa's personal collection. Included in the business records are invoices, receipts for works sold, yearly sales and purchase ledgers, checks for artwork purchases, and index card files recording sales. Legal records include files related to litigation, primarily Lebenstein v. Lejwa. The collection includes film reels and audio recordings of lectures, broadcasts, and exhibits from the 1960s-1990s. It also includes two film reels from a French television program about Jean Arp.
Among the personal records are biographical information, correspondence, legal records mostly related to the settlement of Arthur Lejwa's estate, a significant quantity of snapshots, negatives and slides, and newspaper clippings chronicling Arthur Lejwa's work as a biochemist and the Robert Gould Research Foundation. Arthur Lejwa's scientific career is also represented in biographical information, publications, research notebooks, and photographs. Much of the personal correspondence is from 1939-1951 and is written in Polish, Yiddish and German. The Lejwa's philanthropic donations, especially in Israel, are documented in correspondence, papers, and photographs. Many of the photographs and photo albums record Madeleine Lejwa's travels in the 1970s-1990s.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 8 series. The series are generally arranged alphabetically by type of material or subject, and chronologically thereafter.
Series 1: Correspondence, 1920-1995 (Boxes 1-2; 1.4 linear foot)
Series 2: Artists' Files, 1916-1996 (Boxes 2-6, 25; 4.3 linear feet)
Series 3: General Business Files, 1950-1994 (Boxes 6-8; 2.3 linear feet)
Series 4: Printed Materials, 1931-1996 (Boxes 9-10, 25; 1.2 linear feet)
Series 5: Photographs, circa 1920s-1994 (Boxes 10-16, 24-25; 7 linear feet)
Series 6: Legal Records, 1938, 1959-1988 (Box 17; 0.8 linear feet)
Series 7: Personal Papers of Arthur and Madeleine Chalette Lejwa, 1925-1999 (Boxes 17-21, 25; 3.7 linear feet)
Series 8: Motion Picture Film, Audio, and Video Recordings, circa 1950s-1995 (Boxes 21-23, 26; 2.7 linear feet)
Arp, Jean, 1887-1966; Bill, Max, 1908-1994; Diller, Burgoyne, 1906-1965; Fangor, Wojciech, 1922-; Fuller, Sue, 1914-; Gonzalez, Roberta; González, Julio, 1876-1942; Lejwa, Arthur; Lejwa, Madeleine Chalette, 1914-1996; Moholy-Nagy, László, 1895-1946; Reimann, William; Rickey, George; Smith, Leon Polk, 1906-1996; Vasarely, Victor, 1906-1997; Weber, Max, 1881-1961; Art dealers--New York (State)--New York; Art galleries, Commercial--New York (State)--New York; Biochemistry; Lectures; Motion pictures (visual works); Notebooks; Photographs; Sound recordings
- Correspondence, 1920-1995; Series 1; 1.4 Linear feet Boxes 1-2
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains Galerie Chalette correspondence with artists, business contacts, customers, and friends. Some of the correspondence includes business records such as loan agreements, invoices, and exhibition arrangements. More correspondence may be found in Series 2: Artists' Files, Series 3: General Business Files, and Series 7: Personal Papers.
  Arrangement note
  This series is arranged alphabetically by subject, then chronologically. General chronological correspondence is filed at the end of the series.
  - Leon Chalette, 1950-1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Desa Foreign Trade Company, 1960-1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Donations, 1971-1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Galerie Denise Rene, 1920, 1958-1962 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Galleria Pogliani, 1960-1964 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - William Lieberman, Museum of Modern Art, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - General Chronological Correspondence, 1946-1954 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - General Chronological Correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - General Chronological Correspondence, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - General Chronological Correspondence, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - General Chronological Correspondence, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - General Chronological Correspondence, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
  - General Chronological Correspondence, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 14-15)
  - General Chronological Correspondence, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 16-17)
  - General Chronological Correspondence, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 18-19)
  - General Chronological Correspondence, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 20-21)
  - General Chronological Correspondence, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - General Chronological Correspondence, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - General Chronological Correspondence, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - General Chronological Correspondence, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - General Chronological Correspondence, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - General Chronological Correspondence, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - General Chronological Correspondence, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - General Chronological Correspondence, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - General Chronological Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - General Chronological Correspondence, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - General Chronological Correspondence, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - General Chronological Correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - General Chronological Correspondence, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - General Chronological Correspondence, 1981-1984 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - General Chronological Correspondence, 1985-1989 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - General Chronological Correspondence, 1992-1995 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Artists' Files, 1916-1996; Series 2; 4.3 Linear feet Boxes 2-6, 25
  This series contains files collected by Galerie Chalette primarily on artists the gallery represented. Files include correspondence and information about exhibitions and sales. Significant artist files include Jean Arp, Burgoyne Diller, Wojciech Fangor, Sue Fuller, and Leon Polk Smith. Artists' correspondence may also be found in Series 1: Correspondence and Series 7: Personal Papers. Financial records pertaining to artists may also be found in Series 3: General Business Files. Photographs of the artists and their artwork may also be found in Series 6: Photographs.
  This series is arranged alphabetically by last name, then chronologically. Some larger artists' files are also arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  - Jankel Adler, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Josef Albers, 1965-1971 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Jean Arp (Box 2)
    - Marguerite Arp, 1968-1996 (Box 2, Folder 14-16)
    - Aubrette Tapestry, circa 1965-1975 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Australia Exhibition, 1974-1984 (Box 2, Folder 18-28)
  - Jean Arp (Box 3)
    - Centennial (1986), 1969-1986 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
    - Clippings, 1960-1978 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Condition Reports, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1960-1969 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1975-1979 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1980-1982, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Drafts of Lectures, circa 1975 (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
    - Exhibition, Correspondence, 1973-1979 (Box 3, Folder 11-14)
    - List of Artwork in Klipstein Catalog, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Monograph, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Nikolais/Louis Foundation, 1976-1994 (Box 3, Folder 17-24)
    - Photocopies of 1924-1954 Letters written by Arp (research file), undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Photographs of Arp, 1939-1964 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Photographs of Arp, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Photographs of Arp, undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Photographs of Arp and Sophie Taeuber-Arp, 1916-1952 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Photographs and Negatives of Artwork, circa 1920s-1959 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Jean Arp (Box 4)
    - Photographs and Negatives of Artwork, 1958-circa 1960s (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Photographs of Artwork, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Exhibition Installation Shots, circa 1960s-1974 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Exhibition Installation Shots, Guggenheim Museum (NY), 1968-1976 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Exhibition Installation Shots, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Exhibition Installation Shots, Carnegie in Pittsburgh, 1975, February-March (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Exhibition Installation Shots, Seattle Art Museum, 1975, July-August (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Photographs of Sculptures, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Negatives of Sculptures (5 copies), undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Slides, Installation Shots, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Printed Material, 1929-1965 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Printed Material, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Printed Material, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Printed Material, 1975-1977 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Printed Material, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 15-16)
    - "Seuil Configuration" Dedication Ceremony, 1972, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Thesis "Alienation, Dada, and Hans Arp,", 1972 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Robert Beauchamp, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Max Bill, 1952-1975 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Nina Borowski, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Pierre Caille, 1962-1979 (Box 4, Folder 22-23)
  - Marc Chagall, 1956-1958 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Corneille (Cornelis Guillaume van Beverloo), 1969 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Antonio Corpora, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Judy Cotton, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Nicolas De Stael, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Edgar Degas, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Gea Panter Delloye, 1963, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Andre Derain, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Burgoyne Diller (Box 4)
    - Artwork Sold or Returned, 1962-1965 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Birmingham Festival of the Arts Exhibition, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Color Structures Exhibition, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Correspondence, 1959-1989 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1961-1981 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Geometric Abstraction in America Exhibition, 1961-1963 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Invoices, 1960-1965 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Legal, 1964-circa 1982 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Photographs, 1938-1963 (Box 4, Folder 40-41)
    - Printed Material, 1960-1965 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Washburn Gallery Exhibition, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Cesar Domela (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, 1958-1964 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Max Ernst, circa 1970s (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Wojciech Fangor (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, 1964-1983 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1964-1966 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1966-1973 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Photographs, 1969-1971 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Printed Material, 1965-1971 (Box 5, Folder 8-9)
    - Sales, 1966-1977 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Sue Fuller (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, 1971-1978 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Photographs, 1965-1983 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Printed Material, 1965-1982 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Sketches, circa 1970s (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Julio Gonzalez, 1961, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Roberta Gonzalez, 1961-1964 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Jose Guerrero, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Phillip Guston, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Barbara Hepworth, 1959, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Carl Holty, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Johannes Itten, 1964, 1971-1973 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Robert Jacobson, 1966, 1978-1982 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Nowego Jorku, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Henri Laurens, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Jon Lebenstein, 1960-1962 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Fernand Léger, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Edward Manet, circa 1928 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Manolo (Emanuel Martinez Hugue), 1957 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Henri Matisse, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Lazlo Moholy-Nagy, 1947, 1960-1967 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - David Novros, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Claes Oldenburg, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Pablo Picasso, 1954-1958 (Box 5, Folder 33-34)
  - Man Ray, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - William Reimann (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, 1963-1981 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Photographs, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Printed Material, 1972-1981 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - George Rickey, 1964-1977 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Lucas Samaras, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Kurt Schwitters, 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Gustave Singier, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Leon Polk Smith (Box 6)
    - Biographical, 1965-circa 1970 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Brooklyn Museum of Art, 1993-1996 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Constellations Exhibition, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1971 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - "Correspondence Blue-Red", 1981 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      Oversized material housed in Box 25, Folder 1.
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1968-1970 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Geometric Paintings Exhibition, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Printed Material, 1965-1971-circa 1980 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - "Torn Drawings" Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Sophie Taeuber-Arp, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Victor Vasarely (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, 1965-1981 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Photographs, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Printed Material, 1968-1978 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Max Weber (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, 1958-1970, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Printed Material, 1916, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Yale Group Accounts (Erwin Hauer, William Reimann, Deborah de Moulpied), 1961-1975 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Leon Polk Smith, "Torn Drawings" Catalog, 1965 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    Oversized material from Box 6, Folder 11.
- General Business Files, 1950-1994; Series 3; 2.3 Linear feet Boxes 6-8
  This series contains business files such as agreements about loans, consignments, sales and purchase ledgers, sale index card files, and shipping. Also included are receipts and invoices for works of art and Galerie Chalette publications. Additional business files may also be found in Series 1: Correspondence, Series 2: Artists' Files, and Series 7: Personal Papers.
  This series is arranged alphabetically by type of material or last name, then chronologically.
  - Agreements, 1953-1965 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Agreements with Chadwyck-Healy, 1971-1981 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Appraisals, 1961-1969 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Bills, 1954-1959 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Bills, 1954-1961 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Bills, 1954-1963 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Bills, 1956-1969 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Bills, 1958-1960 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Bills, Correspondence, 1958-1970 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Bills, Unionsdruckerei Luzern, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Buying Trip Files, circa 1950-1964 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Cancelled Checks, Gallery Purchases, 1963-1987 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Cancelled Checks, Gallery's Donations, 1986-1988 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Consignment Agreements, 1957-1971 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Declarations, 1955-1960 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Degas Bronzes Returned, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Donations of Artwork to Museums, 1963-1970 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - General Receipts, 1958-1986 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Insurance, 1957-1961, 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Inventories, 1957-1963, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Lebenstein Account, 1960-1964 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Arthur Lejwa's Car Injury, 1959-1960 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Lejwa-Bernard Venture, 1955-1959 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Lejwa-Glasser Venture, 1956-1961 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Letters of Gifts and Affadavits, 1952-1973 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Loan Agreements, 1955-1963 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Loan Agreements, 1964-1983 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Merchandise Bills, 1960-1963 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Purchases includes Correspondence, 1958-1977 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Receipts for Works Sold, 1954-1957 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Receipts for Works Sold, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Receipts for Works Sold, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Receipts for Works Sold, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 23-24)
  - Receipts for Works Sold, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 25-26)
  - Receipts for Works Sold, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Receipts for Works Sold, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 28-29)
  - Receipts for Works Sold, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Receipts for Works Sold, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Receipts for Works Sold, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Receipts for Works Sold, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Receipts for Works Sold, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Receipts for Works Sold, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 2-3)
  - Receipts for Works Sold, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Receipts for Works Sold, 1972-1974 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Receipts for Works Sold, 1975-1987 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Report of Theft, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Sales, Schlesinger, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Sales and Purchase Ledgers, 1957-1958 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Sales and Purchase Ledgers, 1964-1967 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Sales and Purchase Ledgers, 1968-1975 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Sales and Purchase Ledgers, 1984-1994 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Sales and Purchase Ledgers (Box 8)
    - Arp, 1960-circa 1994 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Fangor, 1965-1976 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Gonzalez, circa 1963 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Special Accounts, 1960-1969 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Sales and Purchases, 1958-1989 (Box 8, Folder 17-21)
  - Sales File Cards, 1958-1978 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Shipping Records, 1955-1989 (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Printed Materials, 1931-1996; Series 4; 1.2 Linear feet Boxes 9-10
  This series contains various printed material with information about exhibitions, artists, and lectures presented by Madeleine Lejwa. Printed material related to gallery records may also be found in Series 2: Artists' Files.
  The folders are organized alphabetically by type of material, then chronologically.
  - Catalogs, 1961, 1974-1975 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Catalogs, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1957-1959 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1960-1969 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1972-1990 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Dada, circa 1931 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Dada, 1972-1978 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Dada, 1973-1979 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Dada, circa 1978 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1955-1957 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    Oversized material housed in Box 25, Folder 2.
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1963-1964 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1964-1965 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1965-1967 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1968-1970 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1972-1996 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Galerie Chalette Exhibition Catalogs, 1956-1959 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Galerie Chalette Exhibition Catalogs, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 18-19)
  - Galerie Chalette Exhibition Catalogs, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Galerie Chalette Exhibition Catalogs, 1961, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 21)